(
"ai_sub_version": "3.3.0",
"generated_at": "2026-07-15T23:57:55.727573",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.1-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
あー、あー、あー！皆様、おー！
Ah, ah, ah! Hello, everyone!
いいですね！コメント元気だね！
Nice! The comments are so lively!
本日は風真いろは生誕ライブ2026「Wind Trails」に
Today, thank you so much for coming...
ご来場くださいまして、誠にありがとうございます！
...to Kazama Iroha Birthday Live 2026 "Wind Trails"!
いえーい！
Yay!
開演に先立ちまして、皆様にお願いとご案内を申し上げます。
Prior to the show starting, I have a few requests and notices.
開演中、カメラやスマートフォンなどは、
During the performance, regarding cameras and smartphones...
電源を切られると見れなくなって困るので、
If you turn them off, you won't be able to watch, which would suck,
電源は切らず、写真撮影などね、大量にしていただき、
so don't turn them off! Take lots of photos,
当配信のハッシュタグ「風真いろは生誕ライブ2026」で、
and post tons of pictures on social media with the hashtag...
SNSに大量に画像ポストしてください！
...#風真いろは生誕ライブ2026!
目指せ！Xトレンド1位！
Let's aim for the number one trending spot on X!
よろしくお願いいたします！
Thank you for your support!
あ、あの、でもスマホね、いっぱい写真撮ったりすると充電なくなっちゃいそうなんで、
Oh, but taking tons of photos on your phone might drain your battery,
スマホで見てる勢は、えー、充電しっかりしてくださいね！
so if you're watching on your phone, please make sure it's fully charged!
はい、そしてその2！
Alright, number two!
激しく頭を振る、えー、激しくペンライトを振る、などはですね、
Shaking your head or waving your penlight too violently...
あなた様の、ご自宅を破壊する危険性がございますので、
...carries the risk of destroying your home.
破壊されてもですね、こちらでは責任一切負えませんので、
We cannot take any responsibility if your room gets wrecked,
お気をつけください！だめだよ、みんな！
so please be careful! No breaking things, okay?
あ、そしてあと、もう1個、その3！
Oh, and one more thing, number three!
今からハヤシライスを準備しようとしてるやつは、間に合わないからやめな！
If you're thinking of cooking Hayashi rice right now, don't! You won't make it in time!
絶対間に合わないから！
There's absolutely no way you'll make it!
まあね、何か食べたり飲んだりしながら、ぜひね、ゆっくり楽しんでもらえると嬉しいです！
Well, grab something to eat or drink, and I hope you can sit back and enjoy!
それでは、もうそろそろ始まるので、
It's about to start, so...
今しばらくお待ちください！
...please wait just a little longer!
最後まで見てねー！
Watch until the very end, okay!
風真いろは 生誕ライブ 2026 行くよー！
Kazama Iroha Birthday Live 2026, here we go!
「いっせーのーで」で鳴り響いた
With an "un, deux, trois," resounded...
スタートの合図
...the starting signal.
なぞった線で結んだ世界
The world bound by traced lines...
色づけていく ここから
...begins to color from here.
物心がつく頃 すでにここにあった
By the time I understood, it was already here...
僕じゃない誰かの記憶は
...the memory of someone else, not me,
夕日と共に蘇る
returns along with the setting sun.
古ぼけた絵本を取り出して
Taking out a worn-out picture book,
落書きの中に一つの答えを見つけた
I found a single answer within the scribbles.
自分の価値に目を疑って
Doubting my own worth,
どこまでだって落ちていけるの
how far down can I possibly fall?
どこか遠くに消えてしまいたい
I want to disappear somewhere far away.
こんな世界じゃ僕は要らない
In a world like this, I'm not needed.
カウントダウンは始まっているよ
The countdown has already begun.
「いっせーのーで」で声を上げて
With an "un, deux, trois," raise your voice,
聞こえてくるんだ
and it will be heard.
自分の影 of 長さに気づく
Noticing the length of my own shadow...
もうこんな時間だ
"It's already that time."
一等星が顔を出した
The brightest star has shown its face.
届きそうで手を伸ばした
Reaching out my hand as if I could grasp it.
次は僕についてきなよ
"Next, follow after me,"
どんな暗闇でも
"no matter how deep the darkness."
もういいかい？ まだだよ
"Are you ready?" "Not yet."
幕は上がりだした
The curtain has started to rise.
もういいかい？ まだだよ
"Are you ready?" "Not yet."
色づけていく ここから
Coloring begins from here.
10年後の僕らは
Ten years from now, we...
すれ違いばかりで
...will only be passing each other by.
幻想に想いを馳せては
As we lose ourselves in illusions...
「戻れない」そう思い込んだ
...convinced that "we can never go back."
くたびれた心に追い打ちを
Striking another blow to an already tired heart,
あの頃と変わらない夕日も
even the sunset, unchanged since those days,,
なんとも思わない
doesn't make me feel anything anymore.
自分を信じ歩いていければ
If I can believe in myself and keep walking,
どこまでだって登れるのにな
I could have climbed to any height.
カットをまたぐその空白に
In the blank space spanning between cuts,
大切なもの見落としている
I am overlooking what's truly important.
見つけられないと泣き喚く君へ
To you, crying out because you can't find it.
「いっせーのーで」で声を上げて
With an "un, deux, trois," raise your voice,
聞こえてくるんだ
and it will be heard.
自分の影の長さに気づく
Noticing the length of my own shadow...
もうこんな時間だ
"It's already that time."
一等星で駆け抜ける君
You, running past like the brightest star,
くっついていただけの僕でも
even for someone like me who just tagged along,
君の前を走れるからな
I can run ahead of you.
こんな頼りない僕でも
Even for someone as unreliable as me.
宝箱はホコリをかぶったまま無くした
The treasure chest was lost, covered in dust.
鍵はずっと君のポケットの中にあった
The key was in your pocket all along.
散らばっていた全てが今一つに重なる
Everything that was scattered is now overlapping as one.
手を取り始めよう 僕たちの物語
Let's take each other's hands and begin our story.
一度は要らないと思った
Though I once thought I didn't need it,
今なら胸を張れる気がしたんだ
I feel like I can hold my head high now.
愛おしくて
So dear to me.
掛け声はいつも
Our rallying cry is always...
「いっせーのーで」で声を上げて
...with an "un, deux, trois," raise your voice!
With an "un, deux, trois," raise your voice,
聞こえてくるんだ
and it will be heard.
自分の影の長さに気づく
Noticing the length of my own shadow...
もうこんな時間だ
"It's already that time."
一等星が顔を出した
The brightest star has shown its face.
届きそうで手を伸ばした
Reaching out my hand as if I could grasp it.
次は僕についてきなよ
"Next, follow after me,"
どんな暗闇でも
"no matter how deep the darkness."
もういいかい？ まだだよ
"Are you ready?" "Not yet."
泣きじゃくった声で
With a sobbing voice,
もういいかい？ まだだよ
"Are you ready?" "Not yet."
笑う君が見えた
I saw you smiling.
もういいかい？ まだだよ
"Are you ready?" "Not yet."
幕は上がりだした
The curtain has started to rise.
もういいかい？ もういいよ
"Are you ready?" "Yes, I am!"
色づけていく ここから
Coloring begins from here.
はい！というわけで
Alright, everyone!
始まりましたー！
It has finally begun!
風真いろは生誕ライブ2026
Kazama Iroha Birthday Live 2026...
スタート！
...starts now!
みんな、こんばんはー！見えてる？
Good evening, everyone! Can you see me?
はい、ということで本日のハッシュタグはこちら！
Alright, and here is today's hashtag!
こちらね、みんな、いっぱいポストしていっぱいカッコいいとこ撮ってくださいね。頼むよ！
Please use this hashtag, post a lot, and take tons of cool screenshots of me. I'm counting on you!
この風真いろはがイケメンであることを世の中に知らしめられるのは、
The only ones who can let the world know...
お前たちだけ、お前たちだけなので、よろしくお願いします！
...how cool Kazama Iroha is are you guys, so I'm counting on you!
はい、そして今回のライブ、タイトルがついております。
Also, this concert has a title.
「Wind Trails」というタイトルがついておりますが、
It's titled "Wind Trails."
そのまま訳して結構お気づきの方も多かったんですが、
Many of you probably figured out the literal translation,
風の軌跡という、あの、意味を込めて付けさせていただき、
but it carries the meaning of "trail of the wind."
今回ライブ、いろいろ頑張って、考えさせていただきました。
I put a lot of hard work and thought into planning this concert.
なのでね、最後まで楽しんでもらえると嬉しいです。
So, I hope you enjoy it until the very end.
そして1曲目ね、「かくれんぼ」、歌わせていただきました！どうだったかなー？
And for the first song, I sang "Kakurenbo"! How did you like it?
そして、今日、室内ライブだと思ったでしょ？
Also, you thought this was an indoor concert today, right?
見て！
Take a look!
曲中にドームが開きましたー！イェーイ！すごい！
The dome opened during the song! Yay! That was amazing!
やっぱりね、なかなか現地ライブって、できてもさ、青空の下で
Real-life concerts don't often give us the chance...
なかなか歌ってることがないので、
...to sing beneath the open blue sky.
いつか俺たちとお前たちの次元が交わって、空の下で歌えるような世界が
Maybe one day our dimensions will cross, and a world where we can sing together under the sky...
来るかもしれないけど、やってみたくてね。今回は、
...will come, but I really wanted to try it, so this time,
空の下で歌うっていうこの演出をやらせていただきましたー！
I wanted to perform this staging where I sing under the sky!
めっちゃいいでしょ？
Isn't it so great?
ステージもめっちゃかっこいいんで、
The stage is also super cool,
今日はね、たぶんいっぱい見る機会あると思いますが、
so you'll have plenty of chances to see it today.
ゆっくり隅から隅まで。アーカイブ勢もきっといると思うんで、
Take your time looking at every corner. I'm sure the archive-watchers will too,
本当にいろんな細部こだわってるんで、細かく見てくださいね。
because we really paid attention to every detail, so look closely!
ということで、
Anyway...
お水飲んでいいですかね？
Can I drink some water?
お水を、お、うっ、やめろ！
Let me get some water... Whoa, wait, stop!
俺の頭をいじ...うっ、やめっ
Don't touch my head... Ugh, stop that-
頭をいじくり回されて、ヘッドセットになりました。
They messed with my head, and now I'm using a headset.
そして、水が、お水、用意してくれたんだよね。
And they prepared some water for me.
みんなに見える水！
Water that all of you can actually see!
うまい！
So good!
うますぎる！この、この振りはちょっと怒られそうだからもうできないけど、うますぎる！
Too delicious! I might get scolded if I do this pose again, but it's so good!
うまいなー。
Ah, that hits the spot.
これで、あと1時間やるか？そういうわけにはいかないんで、
Should I just do this for another hour? I can't do that,
一回ちょっと返して...
so let me put this away...
それじゃあ、
Well then,
水分補給もさせてもらって、息も整ったんじゃない？
now that I've hydrated and caught my breath,
はい、次の曲、早速やっていきたいと思います！
I'd like to get right into the next song!
それでは次の曲、聴いてください。
Now, please listen to the next song.
「白線」
"Hakusen"
澄み渡った空に白線
A white line in the clear blue sky...
あの地平を超えて
...beyond that horizon!
はい！はい！はい！はい！もっと！はい！はい！
Yes! Yes! Yes! Yes! More! Yes! Yes!
始まりはちょっと軽い期待で その欠片そっとポケットしまって
It started with light expectations, tucking those pieces gently into my pocket
屋上 遠い空の向こうを見てた
On the rooftop, looking beyond the distant sky
この足でどこに行けるかなって わかってないけどわかってるんだ
Wondering where these feet can take me, I don't know, but yet I do
白昼 淡い月に手を伸ばした
Reaching my hand out to the pale moon in broad daylight
掠れたエコー でも答えはもう 初めからちゃんと持っていたんだよ
A faded echo, but I already had the answer right from the start
メイビー この想いは
Maybe this feeling...
マスビー 熱を増して
Must be, heating up...
ほらね、飛べるんだ
See? I can fly!
もっと高く 高く 高くまで 羽ばたいてみたい
I want to flap my wings and go higher, higher, even higher
今日に未来色の軌道描いて 地平の先まで
Drawing a future-colored trail in today, all the way to the horizon
届かない歌はない 迷いはもうない
There is no song that won't reach, I have no doubts anymore
どんな世界も瞬間も揺るがない 愛が在るから
Unwavering in any world, at any moment, because love exists
澄み渡った空に白線
A white line in the clear blue sky
不安と期待とアンビバレント
Anxiety, expectation, and ambivalence
でも声はもう気づいてる
But my voice has already realized
もっと高く 高く 高く 飛んでいける！
I can fly higher, higher, and higher!
途切れ途切れの一縷でも
Even if it's just a broken thread...
紡いでたら「一途」に変ったよ
When I spun them together, they turned into devotion.
あたりさわりない言葉じゃ
With harmless, safe words,
覆いきれないほどのマイワールド
I can't fully cover my own world.
明日で呼ぶ声の持ち主は
The owner of the voice calling in tomorrow...
他でもないこの心だった
...was none other than this heart of mine.
見えないって言っている その言葉も
Even those words saying "I can't see"
「言葉」だと足りないだけ
are just not enough as mere "words."
掴んだもの 落としたもの
The things I grabbed, the things I dropped,
転んだって立って見えた視界から
from the scenery I saw as I fell and stood up again,
ロックユー！解き放って
Rock you! Release it!
フォーユー！響きだして
For you! Start echoing!
景色変えてゆく
The scenery is changing.
まだ遠く遠くまで広がった空に
To the sky that stretches far, far away,
やっと踏み出すこの一歩なんてちっぽけだけど
this first step I'm finally taking is tiny, but...
届かない場所へと続いていく保存
...it continues towards an unreachable place.
どんな風に雨に消えない
No matter the wind or rain, it won't fade...
白線を描く
...as I draw a white line.
もっと高く高くまで羽ばたいていたい
I want to flap my wings higher and higher.
そして彼方色で繋ぐ
And connecting with yonder colors...
地平で待ってて
...wait for me at the horizon.
もう願いに嘘はない
There are no more lies in my wishes.
ここが好き！
I love it here!
どんな世界も瞬間も輝く
Every world and every moment shines...
アイが在るから
...because love is there.
今はただ想うこと言えばいい
Now, I just need to say what I feel:
「愛しているよ！」
"I love you!"
澄み渡った空に白線
A white line in the clear sky,
不安と期待がアンビバレント
anxiety and expectation are ambivalent.
でも「君」はもう気づいてる保存
But "you" already noticed.
もっと高く高く高く飛んでいける
I can fly higher, higher, and higher!
もっと
More...
鏡よ 教えて
Mirror, mirror, tell me,
私の証はどこにあるのだろう
where is my proof of existence?
わからない わからないよ
I don't know, I don't know.
周りと比べたってさ
Even if I compare myself to others,
虚しくなるだけ
it only makes me feel empty.
あのノイズが
That noise...
海鳴りのように涙を奪う
...takes away my tears like the roaring of the sea.
切り取った風景を保存
Taking the cut-out scenery,
道標にしよう そうだ
let's make it our guidepost, yes.
傷ついた感情も
If we can bring along...
連れて行けたら
...even our hurt feelings...
そっと響くカンパネラ
The Campanella gently echoes,
新しい未来を感じてる
I'm feeling a new future.
怖くたって進むしかないでしょう保存
Even if we are scared, we have to move forward, right?
遠くまで
To the far distance...
もっと もっと
More, more...
届けこの祈りよ光となれ
Let this prayer reach, become the light!
もっと もっと
More, more...
少しずつでもいい
Even if it's little by little,
私という答えを
the answer that is myself...
もっと
More...
夜空よ 教えて
Night sky, tell me,
私の証は輝けるのかな
can my proof of existence shine?
見つけたい 見つけたいよ
I want to find it, I want to find it.
誰かの決めたレベルは
The levels set by others
苦しくなるだけ
only make me suffer.
ノイズも力に
I will turn even the noise...
変えるよ 心に誓う
...into strength, I swear to my heart.
錆びついた運命の保存
Let's turn...
歯車を回そう ほら
...the rusted gears of fate, look!
着飾った感情は
Because I will cast aside...
脱ぎ捨てるから
...my dressed-up emotions.
そっと紡ぐシンフォニア
The symphonia gently spun,
叶えたい願いを信じてる保存
I believe in the wishes I want to grant.
胸を張って歌うしかないでしょう
We just have to sing with our heads held high,
全力で
with all our might!
もっと もっと
More, more...
やがて希望の歌に変わる日まで
Until the day it finally turns into a song of hope.
もっと もっと
More, more...
悩みながらでいい
It's fine to worry as we go,
全てが宝物
everything is a treasure.
いつの日かこの声を
If one day, this voice...痕跡が残る保存
受け取ってくれたなら
...is received by you,
この言葉を君に保存
I give these words to you:
もう大丈夫 一人じゃない
"It's alright now, you are not alone."
強い想いを
These strong feelings...
繋ぐよ
...I will connect them.
一歩踏み出してみた
I tried taking a step forward,
優しく世界は微笑む保存
and the world gently smiles.
高鳴る気持ちに身を任せて
Surrendering to this rising excitement,
さあ行こう
let's go!
...カンパネラ
...the Campanella.
新しい未来を感じてる
I can feel the new future.
怖くたって進むしかないでしょう
Even if I'm scared, I have no choice but to move forward, right?
遠くまで
To somewhere far away...
届けこの祈りよ 光となれ
Reach out, my prayer! Become the light.
もっと もっと
More and more...
少しずつでもいい「私」という答えを
Even if it's little by little, the answer called "myself"...
もっと... もっと... もっと...
More... and more... and more...
雨とペトラ
[Title: Rain and Petra]
誰かが言った
Someone once said...
いつか空は灰になって落ちるって
...that someday the sky will turn to ash and fall.
妄想の世の中で日々を喰らっている
I'm devouring my days in a world of delusions.
境界線を引いてしまうのも
Drawing a boundary line...
今日、感覚のせいにして
...blaming it on my senses today.
街の灯の海で居場所を探している
I'm searching for where I belong in a sea of city lights.
どこへ行くにも
No matter where I go,
この足は
these feet of mine...
退屈に染まって動かない
...are stained with boredom and won't move.
少しだけ先の
Even though all I want to see...
景色が見たいだけなのにな
...is just a little bit of the scenery ahead.
雨が降ったら 雨が降ったら きっと
When the rain falls, when the rain falls, surely...
頬を濡らしてしまう
...it will wet my cheeks.
枯れてしまった色ですら
Even the withered colors...
愛しくなるのに
...become dear to me.
目を瞑ったら 目を瞑ったら もっと
If I close my eyes, if I close my eyes, even more...
遠く霞んでしまう
...they will grow hazy in the distance.
煩くなった雨の音
The sound of the rain has become noisy.
笑い飛ばしてくれ
Laugh it away for me!
誰かが言った
Someone once said...
いつか溜息は夜に化けて歌を歌う
...that someday, our sighs will turn into night and sing.
妄想の世の中で日々を喰らっている
We're devouring the days within a world of delusion.
優しい嘘を
Because we retraced...
なぞったせいで
...those gentle lies...
離れる声に気付かない
...I didn't notice the fading voice.
溶けた月が
The melted moon...
足元に落ちて
...fell at my feet...
静かに揺れていた
...and quietly shimmered.
夜が降ったら 夜が降ったら きっと
When the night falls, when the night falls, surely...
今日を責めてしまう
...it will blame today.
満たされない日々の底で
At the bottom of these unfulfilled days...
夢を見ているだけ
...I'm simply dreaming.
目を逸らしても 目を逸らしても ずっと
Even if I look away, even if I look away, forever...
後悔と哀の隙間
...in the gap between regret and sorrow...
取り残されてしまう前に
...before I get left behind...
手を伸ばしてくれ
...give me your hand!
雨が降ったら 雨が降ったら きっと
When the rain falls, when the rain falls, surely...
湿るアスファルトを背に映して俯いた
I hung my head, with the damp asphalt reflected on my back.
独りぼっちで
All by myself,
また明日に期待をして
I place my hopes in tomorrow once again.
雨が降ったら 雨が降ったら きっと
When the rain falls, when the rain falls, surely...
頬を濡らしてしまう
...it will wet my cheeks.
枯れてしまった色ですら
Even the withered colors...
愛しくなるのに
...become dear to me.
目を瞑ったら 目を瞑ったら もっと
If I close my eyes, if I close my eyes, even more...
遠く霞んでしまう
...they will grow hazy in the distance.
煩くなった雨の音
The sound of the rain has become noisy.
笑い飛ばしてくれ
Laugh it away for me!
群青讃歌
[Title: Ultramarine Anthem]
繋がっていたいって信じられる言葉
The words that let me believe we want to stay connected
だってもう昨日の僕らにおさらば
Because we've already said goodbye to the us of yesterday
青い春を過ごした
We spent our blue youth
遠い稲妻
with a distant lightning strike
そっと泣いて 前だけを向けたら
If I could just weep softly and look forward,
きっとどんなに楽になれていたろうな
how much easier it would have surely been
この心を揺らした
That single thread of hope
一縷の望みは
which shook my heart
ないものねだりは辞めた 未完成人間
I've stopped wishing for the impossible, incomplete human
素晴らしい世界だけが 答えを握ってる
Only this wonderful world holds the answer
諦めてしまうほど
So much that you might give up,
この先たくさんの
there are many
後悔が君を待ってるけど
regrets waiting for you ahead, but...
もうない 迷いはしないよ
No more, I won't hesitate anymore
この傷も愛しく思えてしまうほど
To the point that even these wounds feel precious
重ねてしまうよ
I'll keep piling them on
不格好なまんまでいいから
Because it's fine to be clumsy
走れ その歩幅で
Run, at your own pace
走れ 声轟かせてくれ
Run, let your voice roar
期待と不安を同じくらい抱きしめて
Embracing both expectations and anxiety in equal measure
君と今を紡ぐ未来照らして
Illuminate the future that weaves "now" with you
顔も名前も知らない僕たちが
We, who don't know each other's faces or names,
たった1つの音をかき鳴らす
strum a single sound
いたずらみたいな奇跡のような刹那
A fleeting moment like a mischievous miracle
あっという間に流れる時が
Time that flows by in the blink of an eye,
ありのままで在り続ける怖さが
and the fear of continuing to stay as we are
失った時間は取り戻せないけれど
We can't take back the lost time, but...
過去を
If you do nothing
振り返ってばかりじゃ
but look back at the past,
泣いたっていいんだ
it's okay to cry
悔しさと痛みだけが
Because only the frustration and pain
君を肯定するから
will validate who you are
大人になったら忘れてしまうの
Will we forget it when we grow up?
君との約束をした場所は
The place where I made a promise with you......
もうない
is no longer there
覚えていたいよ
I want to remember it
思い出も愛しく思えてしまうほど
To the point that even memories feel precious
重ねてしまうよ
I'll keep piling them on
不格好なまんまでいいから
Because it's fine to be clumsy
その声はどこまでも鳴り響いて
Let that voice resound forever and ever
確かな理由を抱いてここまで来たんだ
Holding a certain reason, I've come this far
まだ終わらない旅路なんだ
This is a journey that hasn't ended yet
いつしか想いは形になる
Someday, our feelings will take shape
この真っ白に染まる朝
This morning dyed in pure white
忘れられないまま
Remaining unable to forget,
だから
and so...
諦めてしまうほど
So much that you might give up,
この先たくさんの
there are many...
もうない 迷いはしないよ
No more, I won't hesitate anymore
かけがえのないもの 溢れてしまうよ
The things that are irreplaceable are overflowing
答えは君のその手の中に
The answer is inside your hands
離さないで
Don't let go of it
物語は一歩前へ
The story takes a step forward
諦めてしまうほど
So much that you might give up,
この先たくさんの
there are many
後悔が君を待ってるけど
regrets waiting for you ahead, but...
もうない
No more,
迷いはしないよ
I won't hesitate anymore
この傷も愛しく思えてしまうほど
To the point that even these wounds feel precious
重ねてしまうよ
I'll keep piling them on
不格好なまんまでいいから
Because it's fine to be clumsy
走れ その歩幅で
Run, at your own pace
走れ 声轟かせてくれ
Run, let your voice roar
期待と不安を同じくらい抱きしめて
Embracing both expectations and anxiety in equal measure
君と今を紡ぐ未来照らして
Illuminate the future that weaves "now" with you
六兆年と一夜物語
A Tale of Six Trillion Years and a Night
名もない時代の集落の
In a village of a nameless era,
名もない幼い少年の
lived a nameless young boy,
誰も知らないおとぎばなし
in a fairy tale that no one knows
産まれついた時から
Since the moment I was born,
忌み子 鬼の子として
treated as an unwanted demon child,
その身に余る 罰を受けた
I received a punishment too great for my body to bear.
悲しいことは 何も無いけど
There is nothing to be sad about, but...
夕焼け小焼け 手を引かれてさ
as the sunset glows, my hand is taken and I am led away.
知らない 知らない 僕は何も知らない
I don't know, I don't know, I don't know anything!
叱られた後のやさしさも
Not even the kindness after being scolded,
雨上がりの手の温もりも
nor the warmth of a hand after the rain.
でも本当は 本当は 本当は 本当に
But actually, actually, actually, I am really...
寒いんだ
...so cold.
死なない 死なない 僕はなんで死なない？
I won't die, I won't die, why won't I die?
夢のひとつも 見れないくせに
Even though I can't even have a single dream.
誰も知らない おとぎばなしは
This fairy tale that no one knows
夕焼けの中に吸い込まれて消えてった
was swallowed up by the sunset and disappeared.
吐き出す様な暴力と
With violence spat out like bile,
蔑んだ目の毎日に
and days filled with eyes of contempt,
君はいつしか そこに立ってた
before I knew it, you were standing there.
話しかけちゃだめなのに
Even though I wasn't supposed to speak to you,
「君の名前が知りたいな」
"I want to know your name."
ごめんね 名前も 舌も無いんだ
I'm sorry, I have no name, nor a tongue.
僕の居場所は 何処にも無いのに
Even though there is no place for me anywhere,
「一緒に帰ろう」 手を引かれてさ
"Let's go home together," you said, taking my hand.
知らない 知らない 僕は何も知らない
I don't know, I don't know, I don't know anything!
君はもう子供じゃないことも
Not even that you are no longer a child,
慣れない他人の 手の温もりは
nor that the unfamiliar warmth of someone else's hand
ただ本当に 本当に 本当に 本当のことなんだ
is actually, actually, actually, truly real.
やめない やめない 君はなんでやめない？
You won't stop, you won't stop, why won't you stop?
見つかれば殺されちゃうくせに
Even though you'll be killed if they find you.
雨上がりに 忌み子がふたり
Two unwanted children after the rain,
夕焼けの中に吸い込まれて消えてった
were swallowed up by the sunset and disappeared.
日が暮れて 夜が明けて
The sun set, the night broke,
遊び疲れて つかまって
we grew tired of playing and were caught.
こんな世界 僕と君以外 みんな居なくなればいいのにな
In a world like this, I wish everyone but you and me would disappear...
みんな居なくなればいいのにな
I wish everyone else would just disappear.
知らない 知らない 声が聞こえてさ
I don't know, I don't know, but a voice can be heard!
僕と君以外の 全人類
Every single human being besides you and me,
抗う間もなく 手を引かれてさ
without even time to resist, was led away by the hand,
夕焼けの中に吸い込まれて消えてった
and swallowed up by the sunset, disappearing.
知らない 知らない 僕は何も知らない
I don't know, I don't know, I don't know anything!
これからのことも 君の名も
Not what lies ahead, nor your name.
今は 今は これでいいんだと
But for now, for now, "this is fine,"
ただ本当に 本当に 本当に 本当に思うんだ
is what I truly, truly, truly, truly believe.
知らない 知らない あの耳鳴りは
I don't know, I don't know, but that ringing in my ears...
夕焼けの中に吸い込まれて消えてった
was swallowed up by the sunset and disappeared.
風を置いて
Leaving the wind behind,
雨を抜けて
breaking through the rain,
咲き誇れ
bloom in full glory!
Star-mine
[Title: Star-mine]
あぁ、夜風に揺られている
Ah, swayed by the night breeze,
折れないように 怯えている
terrified of breaking.
ずっと雨に濡らされている
Soaked continuously by the rain,
またどうしたって 凍えてしまったんだ
once again, I've ended up freezing.
誰か この声に 応答して
Someone, please answer this voice...
痛がるばっかで
As it only hurts,
咲けないままの ハートを
...this heart that is unable to bloom.
あぁ、今 見逃せないくらい 綺麗に
Ah, right now, so beautifully that you can't look away,
咲かせたいんだ
I want to make it bloom!
光っていた未来が
The future that was shining,
ずっと待っていた世界が
and the world that had been waiting all along,
きらめく音の中にあるなら
if they are within this sparkling sound...
最低で 最悪な涙も
Then even the lowest, worst tears,
痛がりで 嫌いな声も
and the painful, hated voice,
連れていきたいんだ 全部
I want to take them all along!
不完全な 毎日が
These incomplete everyday lives,
一瞬のカケラたちが
and the fragments of moments,
重なって こんな歌を奏でたら
if they overlap and play a song like this...
それは
...then that,
言葉だけじゃ 届かない距離を
surely leaps over the distance that words alone cannot reach,
きっと飛び越えて 結ぶ
connecting us together.
きっと輪を描いていく
Surely, it will draw a circle.
一・二・三・四・五・六・ステップ踏んで
1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, take a step,
ほら 波に乗って 気取って 浮いて
look, ride the wave, show off, and float.
手を回せ 回せ グルーヴを回せ
Spin your hands, spin them, spin the groove,
フワッとステップ踏んで 今夜は止まんない
take a light step, tonight we won't stop.
迷ったら踊れ 事態は切実さ
If you're hesitant, dance! The situation is urgent,
お構いなしの稲妻鳴らして
so strike with carefree lightning.
声を枯らせ 泥だらけになってもいい 生きていたい
Let your voice go hoarse, it's okay to get muddy, I want to live!
今夜 あの空で合流して
Tonight, let's meet up in that sky,
朝が満たすまで
until the morning fills us.
それぞれの星を探そう
Let's look for our respective stars.
ねえ 今
Hey, right now,
同じこと思っていたんだって
you were thinking the same thing, right?
ほら 話さなくても分かり合えた
Look, we understood each other without even speaking.
あぁ こんな嬉しさを
Ah, this kind of happiness...
ずっと歌ってみたかった
I've always wanted to sing about it.
光っていた未来が ずっと待っていた世界が
Because the shining future and the world we've been waiting for
きらめいて目の前にあるから
are glittering right in front of us.
瞬きの刹那まで このストーリーの最後まで
Until the blink of an eye, until the end of this story,
輝く花でいたいんだ
I want to remain a shining flower.
不完全な私たちが 一瞬の欠片たちが
If our imperfect selves, these fragments of a moment,
重なって今度こそ奏でたら
overlap and play together this time,
それは夢見るだけじゃ叶わない想いをずっと新しくしてく
it will keep renewing the feelings that won't come true just by dreaming.
ずっと追いかけていこう
Let's keep chasing them forever.
風を抱いて
Embracing the wind,
雨を抜けて
passing through the rain,
咲き誇れ
bloom in full glory
満天の空へ
towards the star-filled sky!
世界中のすべての人間に好かれるなんて気持ち悪いよ
It's creepy to be liked by everyone in this world.
だけど一つになれない教室で
But in a classroom where we can't become one,
君と二人 手を繋いでいたいの
I want to hold hands with you, just the two of us.
数の暴力に白旗をあげて
I'll raise the white flag to the tyranny of numbers,
悪感情を殺してハイチーズ
suppress my ill feelings and say cheese.
ポストトゥルースの甘いディープキス
A sweet, post-truth deep kiss...
エロく歪んでるラブアンドピース
A warped, erotic love and peace.
自己中の光線銃 乱射する
Firing a self-centered ray gun wildly,
強者のナンセンス
the nonsense of the strong.
オートクチュールで作る
Creating with haute couture
殺しのライセンス
a license to kill.
分断を生んじゃった椅子取りゲーム
A game of musical chairs that created division,
無痛分娩で授かるベイブ
a baby born through painless labor.
壮大な内輪ノリを歴史と呼ぶ
We're calling a grandiose in-joke "history."
生きたいが死ねと言われ
I want to live but I'm told to die.
死にたいが生きろと言われ
I want to die but I'm told to live.
生きたいが死ねと言われ
I want to live but I'm told to die.
死にたいが生きろと言われ
I want to die but I'm told to live.
幸せ自慢はダメ？
Is it wrong to boast of my happiness?
不幸嘆いてもダメ？
Is it wrong to grieve over my unhappiness?
図々しい言葉を避け
Avoiding impudent words,
明るい未来のため
for our glorious future.
さんはい
One, two...
「この世には息もできない人が沢山いるんですよ」
"There are many people in this world who can't even breathe."
さんはい
One, two...
「この世には息もできない人が沢山いるんですよ」
"There are many people in this world who can't even breathe."
あちらが立てば こちらが立たず
If I'm true to one side, I'm false to the other.
譲り 奪い 守り 行き違い
We give, we take, we protect, we misunderstand.
地雷原で立ち止まり
Stopping in the minefield...
大人しく犬になるんだワン
I'll obediently become a dog, woof.
ノンブレス・ノンブレス・ノンブレス・ノンブレス・オブリージュ
Non-breath, non-breath, non-breath, non-breath oblige,
I love you
息苦しい日々の水面下
Under the surface of my suffocating days,
ゆらゆらと煙る血の花
a flower of blood smokes and flickers.
僕らは
We use our
コンプレックス・コンプレックス・コンプレックス・コンプレックスを武器に
complexes, complexes, complexes, complexes as weapons
争う
to fight.
それぞれの都合と自由のため
For the sake of our convenience and freedom,
息を止めることを強制する
we obligate ourselves to hold our breath.
息が詰まる 息が詰まる 息が詰まる 息が詰まる
I can't breathe, I can't breathe, I can't breathe...
生きたいが死ねと言われ
I want to live but I'm told to die.
死にたいが生きろと言われ
I want to die but I'm told to live.
生きたいが死ねと言われ
I want to live but I'm told to die.
死にたいが生きろと言われ
I want to die but I'm told to live.
まともな人たちが怖いよ
I'm afraid of decent people
正当防衛と言ってチェーンソーを振り回す
who wield chainsaws saying it's self-defense.
愛燦燦 春爛漫
Brilliant love, brilliant spring...
大事なものが消えていくよ
Important things are slowly disappearing.
さんはい
One, two...
「この世には愛も知らない人が沢山いるんですよ」
"There are many people in this world who don't even know love."
さんはい
One, two...
「この世には愛も知らない人が沢山いるんですよ」
"There are many people in this world who don't even know love."
共感 羨望 嫉妬 逆恨み 黒い涙がこぼれ落ち
Sympathy, envy, jealousy, resentment, black tears falling down.
醜い感情が吹き出し
My ugly emotions burst out
真っ白い鳥になるんだな
and become a snow-white bird.
ノンブレス・ノンブレス・ノンブレス・ノンブレス・オブリージュ
Non-breath, non-breath, non-breath, non-breath oblige,
I love you
深海魚と泳ぐ氷点下
Swimming with deep-sea fish below the freezing point,
見上げているザラメの星
looking up at the stars of granulated sugar.
僕らは
We don't
直接・直接・直接・直接 手を下さないまま
directly, directly, directly, directly do anything in person.
想像力を奪う液晶越しに
Through the liquid crystal that robs our imagination,
息の根を止めて安心する
we hold our breaths and feel secure.
ノンブレス・ノンブレス・ノンブレス・ノンブレス・オブリージュ
Non-breath, non-breath, non-breath, non-breath oblige,
I love you
それぞれの都合と自由のため
For the sake of our convenience and freedom...
...強制する
...compelling us to hold our breath.
息が詰まる 息が詰まる 息が詰まる 息が詰まる
I can't breathe, I can't breathe, I can't breathe, I can't breathe...
息が詰まる 息が詰まる 息が詰まる...
I can't breathe, I can't breathe, I can't breathe...
息を止める 息を止める 息を止める 息を止める
I hold my breath, I hold my breath, I hold my breath, I hold my breath...
息を止める 息を止める 息を止める...
I hold my breath, I hold my breath, I hold my breath...
ノンブレス・オブリージュ ノンブレス・オブリージュ ノンブレス・オブリージュ
Non-breath, non-breath, non-breath oblige...
ノンブレス・オブリージュ I love you
Non-breath oblige, I love you.
それぞれの好きを守るため
To protect what each of us loves,
君と防空壕で呼吸する
I breathe inside the bomb shelter with you.
酸素が足りない...
I don't have enough oxygen...
酸素が足りないんですけど...
はい。
Yes.
が、続けてやらせていただきました。
But I went right ahead and performed it!
はい、いかがだったでしょうか。
So, how did you like it?
昨日の配信でも話したんですけど、あの、一部人間じゃないやつがあるって言ってたのが、
As I mentioned in yesterday's stream, the one I said has parts that aren't meant for humans...
あのノンブレス・オブリージュと、
...was indeed Non-breath Oblige...
ま、先ほどね、ソロでやらせていただいた、「僕ら1/2の物語」でしたー！
...and "Bokura 1/2 no Monogatari" which I just performed solo!
はい。
Yes.
ちょっと、純粋にすごく心配だったんですけど、
To be honest, I was really worried about it,
なんとかね、なんとかなって良かったという、今はすごい、安心で今震えております。
but I'm so glad I somehow pulled it off. Right now, I'm shaking with relief.
はい。というわけで、ここまでたくさん見ていただきましたが、
Yes. And so, you've watched a lot up to this point,
皆さん、いかがですか？
everyone, how do you like it?
ゲストもね、めっちゃ来てもらって。
We've also had so many guests come on!
あずきちと、あと、みお先輩、フレア先輩、あとルイ先輩、ねね先輩。
AZKi-chan, Mio-senpai, Flare-senpai, Lui-senpai, and Nene-senpai...
ありがとうございました！
Thank you so much!
あの、本当にみんなと歌ってみたい曲を、自分が好きなやつを、
I chose songs that I really wanted to sing with everyone, my favorites,
この人にこれを歌ってるところ聞きたいっていう気持ちで選んで、一緒にね、やらせていただきました。本当に、
with the feeling of "I want to hear this person sing this song." And we got to perform them together. Truly,
ありがとうございます。先輩たち、ありがとう！
thank you so much. Thank you, senpais!
ふう...ちょっと、一回、水飲んでもいいか？水を飲ませてくれ。
Sigh... Can I have a quick drink of water? Let me drink some water.
はい、よし。
Okay, there we go.
はい。
Alright.
はい、ちょっと落ち着きました。
Okay, I've calmed down a bit.
はい。ということで、まだまだ続くんでね、次の曲行きたいと思うんですけど、
So, we still have more to go, and I'd like to move on to the next song...
次の曲は、あの、昨日のトークでもめっちゃリクエスト上がってて、
For the next song, there were so many requests in yesterday's talk,
で、その前からずっとリクエスト上がってて、
and it's been requested heavily since way back.
いやこれ生誕ライブにやりたいなってことで、
I've been saving it, thinking "I definitely want to do this for my birthday live!"
ずっととっておいた曲です。
I've been keeping it just for today.
なんで、楽しんでもらえると嬉しいです。
So I hope you enjoy it.
それでは、次の曲聞いてください。
Now, please listen to the next song...
「ray」
..."ray."
お別れしたのはもっと前の事だったような
I now feel like the day we said goodbye is further away than it really is;
悲しい光は封じ込めて踵すり減らしたんだ
I’ve worn my heels down sealing away that sorrowful light.
君といた時は見えた今は見えなくなった
The things I saw when I was with you are invisible to me now;
透明な彗星をぼんやりとでもそれだけ探している
All that’s left is a ghost-like comet that’s become the only thing I search for.
しょっちゅう唄を唄ったよその時だけのメロディーを
I sang a song with a melody made up of that time with you,
寂しくなんかなくなかったよちゃんと寂しくなれたから
But it wasn’t sad at all, since I now know what sadness really is.
いつまでどこまでなんて正常か異常かなんて
I don’t even have time to think about "when" or "how far", normal or abnormal.
考える暇も無い程歩くのは大変だ
Just moving forward is hard enough.
楽しい方がずっといいよごまかして笑っていくよ
Life is better when you’re having fun, so I’ll pretend like we’re always smiling.
大丈夫だあの痛みは忘れたって消えやしない
Don’t worry; even if I forget this pain, it will never fade away.
理想で作った道を現実が塗り替えていくよ
Reality is beginning to overwrite the road I paved with ideals,
思い出はその軌跡の上で輝きになって残っている
And my memories are left glittering upon the path I’ve taken.
お別れしたのは何で何のためだったんだろうな
Why did we part ways? What were we trying to accomplish?
悲しい光が
That sorrowful light...
悲しい光が僕の影を
A sad light casts my shadow
前に長く伸ばしている
long and far ahead of me.
時々熱が出るよ
Sometimes I run a fever,
時間がある時眠るよ
and I sleep whenever I have the time.
夢だと解るその中で
In a dream I know is just a dream,
君と会ってからまた行こう
I'll meet you, and then let's go again.
晴天とはほど遠い
Far from a clear blue sky,
終わらない暗闇にも
even in the never-ending darkness,
星を思い浮かべたなら
if I imagine the stars,
すぐ銀河の中だ
I am instantly in the middle of a galaxy.
あまり泣かなくなっても
Even if I don't cry as much anymore,
靴を新しくしても
even if I get brand new shoes,
大丈夫だ あの痛みは
I'll be fine, because that pain...
忘れたって消えやしない
won't fade away even if I forget it.
伝えたかった事がきっとあったんだろうな
There must have been something I wanted to tell you.
おそらくありきたりなんだろうけど こんなにも
It was probably something cliché, but still, so much so...
お別れした事は
Our parting...
出会った事と繋がっている
is connected to our meeting.
あの透明な彗星は
That transparent comet...
透明だからなくならない
won't disappear because it's transparent.
◯✕△どれかなんて
Circles, crosses, or triangles... which is it?
皆と比べてどうかだなんて
And how it compares to everyone else...
確かめる間も無い程
With no time to even check,
生きるのは最高だ
living is the absolute best.
あまり泣かなくなっても
Even if I don't cry as much anymore,
ごまかして笑っていくよ
I will fake a laugh and keep going.
大丈夫だ あの痛みは
I'll be fine, because that pain...
忘れたって消えやしない
won't fade away even if I forget it.
大丈夫だ この光の
I'll be fine, because at the beginning...
始まりには君がいる
of this light, you are there.
はい、ということで、rayでした！
Yes, and with that, that was "ray"!
あぁ、どうだったでしょうか？
Ah, how was it?
めっちゃエモい、エモい、エモい感じになりましたね。はい。
It turned out to be very emotional, emotional, emotional. Yes.
ちょっと一瞬水飲んでいいですか？
Can I drink some water for a second?
あ、うまい
Ah, delicious.
飲んでも飲んでも減らない水。いいだろう？風真いろは特注だぜ。
Water that doesn't decrease no matter how much you drink. Great, right? It's custom-made for Kazama Iroha.
よし、はい！
Alright, yes!
というわけで、次のね、曲にいきたいと思うんですけど
With that, I'd like to move on to the next song, but...
あの、昨日の配信でちょっと匂わせをしたんですが、本日はですね
I gave a little hint in yesterday's stream, but today...
あの、視聴者参加型3D生ライブになっておりまして。はい。
this is a viewer-interactive 3D live concert! Yes.
今回はですね、皆さんに投票をしていただいて、次に歌う曲決めたいと思います！
This time, I'd like to have everyone vote to decide the next song we sing!
「なんじゃそりゃ」って思うかもしれないんですけど、視聴者参加型曲決め合戦っていうことです！それでは、テロップどうぞ！
You might think, "What is that?", but it's a viewer-interactive song-deciding battle! Now, bring up the graphic, please!
じゃじゃーん！
Ta-da!
えー、「ANIMA」か「ただ声一つ」
It's either "ANIMA" or "Tada Koe Hitotsu" (Just One Voice).
どっちか！で、投票が少なかった方も、この後メンバーシップ限定のアンコールライブで歌いますので
Which one will it be? The song with fewer votes will be sung later in the membership-only encore live,
よろしくお願いします！いや、どちらも名曲で迷いますよね
so please look forward to it! Gosh, both are great songs, so it's hard to choose, right?
今、スタッフの人とどっちになるかねっていうのを賭けてます
Right now, I'm making a bet with the staff on which one it will be.
あの、どっちに賭けてるか言わないんですけど、さあ、みんな、これで次回の差し入れが豪華になるか、裏で決まるからな！はい！
I won't say which one I bet on, but everyone, this will determine behind the scenes whether our next refreshments will be fancy! Yes!
というわけで、早速投票を開始していきたいと思います。大体時間は1分くらいですかね？
So, I'd like to start the voting right away. We have about one minute, right?
それでは、用意、スタート！
Now then, ready, start!
届いた？
Did it reach you?
今...
Now...
来たかな？
Did it come through?
おっ、たくさん来た、来た、来た、来た、来た、来た！
Oh, lots of votes are coming in!
はい、じゃあみんな、投票ボタン押してね！
Alright, everyone, press the voting button!
じゃあ、みんなが投票やってる間にゆっくり...
Well, while everyone is voting, slowly...
みんなのこと待つために帰るわ、メインステージ。
I'll head back to the main stage to wait.
じゃ、移動ですよ、移動ー！
Now then, off I go, on the move!
はい、というわけで、皆さん、投票した？
Alright, so, did everyone vote?
できてる？
Did you get it done?
どっちかだよ！
Choose one of them!
両方はちょっとあれだから...
Voting for both is a bit tricky, so...
どっちか、どっちかにお願いします！
Please pick one or the other!
そういえば、今なんだかんだこうやって歩かせてもらっていますが...
By the way, as I walk along like this...
実はね、何気にね...
Actually, you know...
ファーストミッション衣装がね...
Showing off this First Mission Outfit...
見せるのが、ゆっくり見せるのが、初めてだったりするんだけど...
and showing it slowly is actually a first...
そうだ、ここでさ、宣伝しとこう。
Oh right, let me do some promo here.
尺稼ぎじゃないよ！あれ、宣伝ね。
This isn't just to fill time! It's promo, okay?
このあとメインでアフターライブがあるんですけど...
We have an after-live on the main stage next...
その時、その時に、もっとこのカッコいいところを...
and at that time, I'll show you many more...
いっぱい見せますので！
of these cool features!
なんでぜひ良かったらメインのアフターライブにも...
So please, if you'd like, come to the main...
お越しください！っていう宣伝も入れつつ...
after-live! Throwing in that quick promo...
みんな入れた？
Did everyone vote?
Did you all vote?
すごっ、何これ？花道、長くない？
Wow, what is this? Isn't the runway long?
な、長くない？
I-Isn't it really long?
これ、これ現地ライブでもやりたいな。
I'd love to do this at an in-person live show.
はい、もう大分カッコいい風真いろはをいっぱい見せているわけなんですが。
Yes, I've already been showing you a very cool side of myself.
いや、でもどっちかな？これ。
But I wonder which one it'll be?
「ANIMA」はね、みんな。設定の通りの「ANIMA」。
"ANIMA" is, you know, just like the setting.
カッコいい！カッコいい！で。
It's so cool!
「ただ声一つ」はしっとり。しっとり、なんで。
While "Tada Koe Hitotsu" is mellow and emotional.
これ好みが分かれると思います。はい、いや、きっとね...
So, preferences might be divided. But surely...
どっちやってもみんなカッコいいって言ってくれるよね？
Whichever it is, you'll still say I'm cool, right?
言ってくれるよね？
You will, right?
え、言って、言ってくれる？あ、言ってくれる！
Wait, will you? Oh, you will!
カメラは言ってくれるということで。
The camera operator nodded yes, so...
はい、というわけで、みんな、もう大丈夫かな？
Alright, so is everyone ready?
オッケー？
Are we good?
じゃあ、そろそろ終わっちゃいますからね。
Then, it's about time to close it.
はい、早く早く、早く投票してね！
Hurry up and cast your votes quickly!
はい、はい、え？
Yes, yes, eh?
終わった？終わったよね？スタッフさん、終わった？
Is it over? It's over, right? Staff, is it done?
終わった？
Is it over?
早かった？歩くの。終わった？
Was my walking too fast? Is it done?
終わった、終わった、終わったかな？
I wonder if it's finished?
あ、なんか終わったらしい。
Ah, looks like it's over.
今、賭けをしているスタッフと睨めっこしてます。
Right now, I'm staring down the staff who placed a bet.
それでは！
Now then!
結果発表タイム！
Time to announce the results!
じゃん！
Ta-da!
アンケートの結果、「ANIMA」になったみたいです！
According to the poll, it looks like it's "ANIMA"!
これ、あの賭けに勝った人の動きです。
This is the victory dance of someone who won the bet.
うぇーい！差し入れ期待してます！よっしゃー！
Yay! I'll be expecting treats! All right!
というわけで、あの賭けにも勝ち、皆さんにも選んでいただき、とてもありがたい限りですね。
So, winning the bet and being chosen by everyone, I'm super grateful.
「ただ声一つ」の方もこのあとメンバーシップ限定で歌いますので、そちらもお楽しみに！
I'll also sing "Tada Koe Hitotsu" on membership after, so look forward to that!
と、いうわけで、早速歌っていきましょうか。
And with that, let's start singing right away.
それでは聞いてください。「ANIMA」。
Now, please listen to "ANIMA".
魂の色は
What color is...
何色ですか
...the color of your soul?
「もういっそ 折れたままで」
"I'd rather it stay broken."
捨てるほど 逃げ出すほど
So much that I'd throw it away, run away from it...
強くないよ ほら
I'm not that strong, you see...
もう一度 鼓動 高鳴る
Once again, my heartbeat quickens.
何が正しいかなんて
As to what is right,
わからないけど
I still do not know, but...
形のないものばかりが
Only the things without shape...
大切になって行く
...become more and more precious.
飾らない言葉だけが
Only those unadorned words
強く結ばれてる
are tightly bound together.
また躓いて 転がって それでも砕けない
Tripping and falling again, yet still unbreakable.
魂の色は 何色ですか
What color is the color of your soul?
ただ傷ついて 強がって それでも見つけたいよ
Just getting hurt, acting tough, yet still wanting to find...
魂のカタチ 確かめてるよ
...and confirm the shape of my soul.
深い地の底で一人
Alone deep under the earth,
扉と鍵を探す
searching for the door and the key.
おとぎ話は ほら
Fairy tales, you see,
泡の様に全部消えて
disappear completely like bubbles,
葛藤 残像だけ
leaving only struggles and afterimages.
次の頁へ
Onto the next page...
伸びてく枝葉が分かれて それぞれの道を行く
Sprouting branches split, each going its own way.
それぞれの道を行く
...and go our separate ways.
寂しい思い出だけが
Only the lonely memories...
強く根を張ってる
...are taking deep root.
まだ貫いて失って それでも挫けない
I still stand firm and lose, but even so, I won't lose heart.
心はどこに 器はどこに
Where is the heart? Where is the vessel?
ただ残されて抜け落ちて それでも伝えたいよ
I'm just left behind and falling out, but even so, I want to convey...
魂の日々を 魂の意志を
...the days of the soul, the will of the soul...
ずっと
...forever.
Forever...
魂の色は
What color is the soul?
何色ですか
What color is it?
赤色ですか
Is it red?
青色ですか
Is it blue?
魂の色は
What color is the soul?
何色ですか
What color is it?
透明な過去に 不透明な明日に
In the transparent past, in the unclear tomorrow...
生きるあなたは何色ですか
...what color are you, living your life?
また躓いて転がって それでも砕けない
I stumble and fall again, but even so, I won't break.
魂の色は 何色ですか
What color is the soul? What color is it?
ただ傷ついて強がって それでも見つけたいよ
I'm just hurt and acting tough, but even so, I want to find it...
魂のカタチ 確かめてるよ
...I am verifying the shape of the soul.
ずっと
Forever...
...forever...
ずっと
...forever.
はい！ということで
All right! And so,
ANIMAを歌わせていただきました！
I performed "ANIMA"!
カロリー高いほうだったな、水、水ください
That was a high-calorie song! Water, please give me some water.
カロリー高いほうだった
That was really high-calorie...
あぶない
That was close.
あ、すいません。あの、ナチュラルにマイクを返すの忘れていました。
Ah, sorry. I totally forgot to return the mic.
やばい、音変になってなかったならいいな、すいません。
Oh dear, I hope the sound didn't go weird. Sorry!
ナチュラルのに。スタッフさんがすっごい手伸ばしてくれたのに、疲れすぎでここ硬直しちゃってた。
I naturally... The staff was stretching their arm out so far, but I was so tired my arm just froze.
はーい
Okay.
水うまい
Water tastes so good.
減らない水のおかげで、生きていけてます。
Thanks to this bottomless water, I'm able to survive.
はい、で、ちょっとこれ返して。
All right, let me return this.
はい！
Okay!
それではですね、ま、ちょっとまだまだ続くんですけど、
So, well, there's still more to come,
ここいらで一旦、重大告知タイムをさせていただきたいと思います！
but at this point, I'd like to have a major announcement time!
じゃ、まずはいつものから行くか！じゃ、まずはこちら！
First, let's start with the usual one! Here it is!
風真いろは、誕生日記念グッズ2026出ます！
Kazama Iroha Birthday Celebration Goods 2026 are coming out!
ドンドコドンドン、ドンドンドン！
Dondokodondon, dondondon!
いや、なんか良さそうなラインナップですね。
Wow, it looks like a really great lineup!
はい、今回もとってもこだわったグッズばかりなんで、皆さん楽しみにしていてほしいです！
Yes, this time too, they're all merchandise we put a lot of care into, so please look forward to them!
では、一つずつ、商品を見ていきましょう。
Now, let's take a look at the items one by one.
まずはこちら！
First is this one!
タペストリーが出ます！
The tapestry is coming!
タペストリー、実は個人グッズで出すの超久しぶりなんですよね。
Actually, it's been a very long time since I last released a tapestry as personal merchandise.
イラストは、もちぷよ先生描き下ろしで、雨上がりの青空の下で
The illustration is drawn by Mochipuyo-sensei. Under the blue sky after the rain,
本当にね、このステージみたいな感じで、ライブをしている風真いろはのイメージで描いていただきました。
she drew it with the image of Kazama Iroha performing a live show, just like on this stage.
ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much!
いや、めっちゃ良いよね。飾ってね！
Wow, it's really nice. Please hang it up!
続いてはこちら！
Next is this one!
フード付きタオル！
The hooded towel!
はい、タペストリーと同じイラストのフード付きタオルです。
Yes, it's a hooded towel with the same illustration as the tapestry.
フード部分はぽこべぇの顔になっており、取り外しが可能となっております。
The hood part has Pokobe's face and is detachable.
いやなんか、こないだね、あの、HoloXのライブあったじゃん？
You know, the other day, there was the HoloX live show, right?
で、なんかダンスの先生に教えてもらったんだけど、
And my dance teacher told me about it,
なんか風真いろは、異様にタオル購入率が良かったらしいな、お前たち。
but apparently, you guys had an unusually high purchase rate for Kazama's towel!
首にいっぱい巻いてくれてえらいぞ！
Good job wrapping them all around your necks!
フード付きタオル！
A hooded towel!
取り外せるんで、これで自忍ぽこべえごっこができるようになります
Since it's removable, you can play-act as Jinin Pokobe with this!
自忍ぽこべえごっこをしたい方
For those of you who want to play as Jinin Pokobe,
まあ、取り外してそのまま飾りたい方もね、どうぞ！
or if you just want to remove it and display it, please go ahead!
はい、そしてお次はこちら！
Alright, and next up is this!
ペットボトルホルダー！
A PET bottle holder!
あの、これは風真いろはさんが欲しいのを作りました！
Um, I made this because it's something I really wanted!
あの、イラストはさめあんこ先生に描いていただきました
The illustration was drawn by Sameanko-sensei.
可愛いでしょ？この真ん中の穴に
Isn't it cute? In this middle hole,
あの、ギュッてペットボトルのところを入れてね
you tightly insert the neck of the PET bottle,
あの、使うやつです、はい
and that's how you use it. Yes!
めちゃくちゃおしゃれです、よかったら使ってください
It's very stylish, so please use it if you'd like.
カバンとかね、付けて持ち運べるんでね
You can attach it to your bag to carry it around!
はい！
Yes!
そしてラストはこちら！
And finally, here's the last one!
はい！実は地味になかった、セーラー服衣装の風真いろはのぬいぐるみ！
Yes! A sailor uniform version of my plushie, which surprisingly didn't exist before!
なんと、ボイス付きです！
And it actually comes with voices!
こちらもさめあんこ先生に原案考えていただきました
Sameanko-sensei also designed the draft for this.
レインポンチョを着た、声が出るぬいぐるみです
It's a voice-playing plushie wearing a rain poncho.
まあ、あの、お腹を握りしめると音が出るらしいぞ
Apparently, it plays sound when you squeeze its tummy!
今のところはな、はい！
At least, for now. Yes!
外出時にカバンなどに付けることもできます。で、ボイスなんですけど
You can also attach it to your bag when you go out. And about the voices...
なんか、天気に関するものを録ったんですよ
I actually recorded things related to the weather!
どんな感じかはまだね、さすがに言えないけど。だけど、あの
I can't tell you exactly what it's like yet, of course. But...
おみくじ感覚で聞いて
you can listen to it like a fortune-telling slip,
あの、その天気にならなかったからと言って、風真いろはを責めないでください
so please don't blame me if the weather doesn't turn out that way!
自己責任で、にぎにぎしてください
Please squeeze it at your own risk!
買ってからのお楽しみです！
Look forward to it after you buy it!
いっぱいありましたが、フルセットを見ていきましょう！
We had a lot of items, but let's check out the full set!
こちら！
Here it is!
今回のグッズはですね、生誕のイメージに合わせてフェス風をテーマに作ってみました
This time, we created the merchandise with a festival theme to match my birthday image.
実用性たっぷりだし、これからの季節にぴったりなんで
It's very practical and perfect for the upcoming season,
よかったら、よろしくお願いします！
so I'd appreciate it if you checked it out!
そしてフルセット購入特典は、こちら！
And the purchase bonus for the full set is this!
数量限定版あります。風真いろはの
There is a limited-quantity version. It includes
直筆サインと箔押し複製メッセージ入りチケット風カード、ちょっとおしゃれな感じですね
a ticket-style card with my handwritten signature and a foil-stamped message. It has a classy feel to it!
そして通常版には、箔押し複製サインとメッセージ入りチケット風カードがついてきます保存版
And the standard version comes with a ticket-style card featuring a foil-stamped signature and message.
えー、さらにどちらにも、えー、ボイスがついてきますね、はい
Furthermore, both versions come with a voice recording. Yes!
「きみと雨宿り」というなんかタイトルのボイスがついてくるんですけど、まあ、ぶっちゃけあの
It's a voice track titled "Sheltering from the Rain with You." Frankly, though...
気になったら聴いてください
please listen to it if you're curious!
ボイスは無理に聴かせたいからね
I really want you to hear this voice track!
はい、ということで、シチュエーションボイスですね。雨宿り系だった気が
Yes, so it's a situation voice. I think it was a sheltering-from-the-rain situation...
なんか照れながら録った気がします！
I feel like I recorded it while feeling embarrassed!
そしてグッズは21時カートオープンです！
And the merchandise cart opens at 21:00!
すみません、あの、生配信につきちょっと時間が押しそうなんですけど
I'm sorry, since this is a live broadcast, we're running a bit behind schedule...
あの、ゆっくり買ってねとは言えず
I can't tell you to take your time buying,
頑張ってください！どうしようもない、ごめん！
so do your best! There's nothing I can do, sorry!
そしてあの、21時からホロメンの多分配信控えてると思うんですけど、あの、何も気にしなくていいんでスタートしてくださいね、はい！
And also, around 21:00, other Hololive members' streams are probably scheduled, but please don't worry about me and just start them, okay? Yes!
はい！そして
Yes! And...
まだまだあります！
there's still more!
まだまだ！それがこちら！
Still more! Here it is!
はい、新曲！
Yes, a new song!
イェーイ！
Yay!
風真いろはさんの新曲が出ます。タイトルは「風向きエントロピー」
I'm releasing a new song! The title is "Kazamuki Entropy."
作詞作曲は「いろはステップ」でもおなじみ、40mPさんにしていただきました！
The lyrics and music were written by 40mP-san, who is also known for "Iroha Step"!
はい！
Yes!
配信後にこちらMVが、えーと、公開されます
After the stream, the MV will be released!
多分、こっそり今マネちゃんがプレミア公開に切り替えてくれているはず
My manager is probably stealthily switching it to a premiere release right now!
楽曲は0時リリースになっております！
The song will be released digitally at midnight!
はい！
Yes!
そしてあの、ちょっと気付いた人もいるかもしれないんですけど
And some of you might have already noticed,
ジャケットの文字は風真いろはさんが自分で書きました、はい。ありがとうございます
but the text on the jacket art was hand-written by me! Yes, thank you very much.
ということで
So with that said,
もう終わっちゃうんですけど
we're already nearing the end,
なんか、すごいトレンド2位とかに入ってるっていう連絡を受けました！うそ！
but I just received word that we're trending at number 2! No way!
あと残り頑張ってくれと言いたいけど
I want to tell you to keep pushing for the top, but...
でもみんな本当にいっぱいポストしてくれてありがとうね！
anyway, thank you all so much for posting so much!
よし、準備できた？
Alright, are you ready?
音の準備は全部できてそうなので
It looks like all the audio setup is complete,
早速、新曲歌っていきたいと思います！
so I'm going to perform my new song right away!
しかし、しかし！
However, however!
今回はちょっと特別なものを用意してきました！
I've prepared something a bit special for this!
ゴンドラ、来い！
Gondola, come on out!
おお！
Oh!
リハーサルで見たけど、やっぱいいなこれ！
I saw it during rehearsal, but this is really great!
ほっ、というわけで
Up we go! So with that,
みんな、ぽこべえがいなくて寂しかったでしょ？
you guys were lonely without Pokobe, right?
今年は、ゴンドラになりました！
This year, he became a gondola!
はい、というわけで、早速やっていくんですが
Yes, so we'll get started right away, but...
ドア、オープン！
Door, open!
イェーイ、ほっ！乗っちゃおうね！
Yay, up! Let's get on!
というわけで！
So with that...
早速、歌っていきたいと思います
I'd like to perform the song right away.
それでは聴いてください。風真いろは、新オリジナル曲
Please listen to my new original song,
「風向きエントロピー」
"Kazamuki Entropy."
風向きエントロピー
作詞・作曲・編曲：40mP
Kazamuki Entropy
Lyrics, Composition, Arrangement: 40mP
ねえ いつからそこにあったの？
Hey, when did you get there?
あまりにも近すぎて気づかなかったよ
It was so close, I didn't even notice.
ずっと私が生まれた日から
You've been by my side
そばにいてくれたのにね
since the day I was born, haven't you?
曖昧で
Ambiguous...
複雑で
...complex...
予測不可能で
...and unpredictable,
気まぐれに変わってゆく空の模様
the ever-changing appearance of the sky.
想像していたより
More than I had imagined...
うまく笑えない
I can't smile properly...
だけどそれ以上に
But even more than that,
世界は優しくて
the world is so gentle.
いつか風が生まれた
One day, a wind was born
足跡が始まる場所
at the place where footprints begin.
あの日の未来が帰って
Even if the future from that day returns
駆けだしたとしても
and starts running...
ここに来るんだろう
I would still end up right here, wouldn't I?
この景色も
This scenery...
この声も
and this voice...
私を彩るすべて
everything that colors my life.
方向なんて
As for the direction,
まだ
I still...
わからないけど
don't know it yet, but...
ただ風の吹くままに
I will just go where the wind blows.
ねえ いつから気づいてたの？
Tell me, since when did you know?
まるで私のこと全部お見通しで
It's like you can see right through everything about me.
苦し紛れにごまかした嘘も
Even the lies I used to scrape by...
君にはバレてたのかな
I wonder if you had them all figured out.
平凡で退屈で
An ordinary, boring,
あくび混じりで
yawn-filled,
変化のないありふれてる時間
and unchanging routine time...
想像していただけじゃ
If I just kept imagining things,
何も変わらない
nothing would change.
だけどそれ以上に
But even more than that,
予測していた以上に
even more than I predicted,
ほら
look,
新しい風が吹いてきて
a new wind has started to blow.
不器用な自分が
And my clumsy self...
愛おしく思えたんだ
started to feel quite precious to me.
いつか風が止んで
Someday, when the wind stops...
足跡が途切れた場所
at the place where footprints fade away...
落とし物探して 拾って
I'll search for lost things and pick them up.
見つけだせたから
Since I managed to find them,
ここにいるんだろう
I must be standing right here.
そっと
Softly,
髪がなびく
my hair flutters in the wind.
いつか風が夢見た
Someday, the wind dreamed...
青空と交わる場所
of the place where it meets the blue sky.
回り道選んで 迷って
Choosing detours and getting lost...
躓いたとしても
even if I stumble along the way,
そこへ行くんだろう
I will still make my way there.
この景色も
This scenery...
この声も
and this voice...
私を彩るすべて
everything that colors my life...
等身大の手で
With my own hands,
握りしめて
I will hold onto them tightly.
想像以上にもっと
More than I ever imagined,
自由な速度で
at a freer pace.
方向なんて
As for the direction,
まだ
I still...
わからないけど
don't know it yet, but...
ただ風の吹くままに
I will just go where the wind blows.
はい！というわけで、ありがとうございました！
And with that, thank you so much!
よいしょ。みんな、すっかり忘れてると思うけど
Alright! I think everyone has completely forgotten, but...
今日これ、これから、記念撮影します！
today, we are going to take a commemorative photo!
そう、お土産があるって言ったっしょ？
That's right! I said there would be a souvenir, right?
これこれ、いや、ちょっと待って、マジで自撮り棒
This, this... No, wait a minute. Seriously, this selfie stick...
これリハーサルでめっちゃ練習したのに！
Even though I practiced with it so much in rehearsal!
自撮り棒下手。あ、いい感じいい感じ。
I'm bad with selfie sticks. Oh, this is good, this is good.
カシャ。
Click!
よし。いけてそう、いけてそう。
Alright, looks like it worked, looks like it worked.
オッケー！
Okay!
はい！というわけで皆さん
So, everyone!
今日お土産ありって言いましたね？
I did say there would be a souvenir today, right?
そうなんです。今日撮った、今この風真がね、自撮り棒で撮った写真が
That's right. The picture that I, Kazama, just took with the selfie stick...
コンビニで、なんとプリントアウトできます！
can actually be printed out at convenience stores!
すごい！
That's amazing!
はい、こちらですね、対象店舗、ファミリーマートさん、ローソンさん、ミニストップさんで
Yes, this one. Available at FamilyMart, Lawson, and Ministop...
本日21時から、ネットで事前購入ができます。
you can pre-purchase online starting from 9 PM today.
お値段がですね、税込300円とのことで、
The price is 300 yen including tax, and...
印刷できるのは、明日6月19日の20時からになっております。
you will be able to print it starting tomorrow, June 19th, from 8 PM.
写真にはですね、複製手書きメッセージ、この後書きますんで。
On the photo, there will be a printed handwritten message, which I'll write after this.
はい、どんな写真が撮れているか、写真下手くそでも怒らないでね？
So please look forward to it. And don't get mad if the photo turned out bad, okay?
内容は買ってから確認してください。
Please check the content after you buy it.
いや、すごいよね？
I mean, isn't that amazing?
ちょっと一足早く皆さんのもとに、手元に残るライブのお土産が用意できればということで
I really wanted to prepare a physical live concert souvenir that you can hold onto,
今回やらせていただきました。お土産あります！
so we put this together. Enjoy your souvenir!
ちょっと皆さん 各自で回収って形で それだけが申し訳ないんですが
I'm sorry that you have to go and collect it yourselves,
お土産ありますので ぜひ気になったらコンビニでプリントしてみてください！
but it's a souvenir! If you're interested, please try printing it at a convenience store!
そして コンビニプリント購入できるのは 7月21日17時59分までです！
Also, the convenience store print will be available for purchase until July 21st at 17:59!
概要欄に 写真購入のリンク、多分今マネちゃんがやってくれてると思いますので よろしくお願いします！
The link to purchase the photo is in the description! My manager is probably putting it up now, so please check it out!
そしてこの後はですね MVの公開と メンバーシップ限定のアンコールライブありますので
And after this, we have the MV release and the membership-exclusive encore live...
そちらも絶対に聴いてくださいね！
...so please make sure to tune in to those as well!
それでは皆さん またお会いしましょう！
Well then, everyone, see you again!
最高の誕生日でした！バイバーイ！
This was the best birthday ever! Bye-bye!